# **ZACHARY WOOD**

### **FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

zacharydavdevelops@gmail.com > 574-549-7491 > LinkedIn > Github > Portfolio > Warsaw, IN

My name is Zach Wood. I am a 20 year old who loves technology. Ever since I was a kid I have been hands on with computers and have learned about them since I was the age of 7. Throughout the rest of my education I studied various amounts of technology from IT Support, to networking and even web design/UX design. In high school I took many coding classes which led me to my love for solving problems. I am now a proud Full Stack Software Engineer ready to make an impact in the tech industry.

Experienced in a wide range of skills including:

LANGUAGES: Javascript, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS DATABASES: SQLite, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, Sequelize

FRAMEWORKS: React, Redux, Express, flask, AWS, docker` TOOLS: Add, These, Here, And, Here

KEY SKILLS: Pair-Programming, Planning, SCRUM, Team Building, Coding Reviews, Version control, Debugging, Online Work

environment

## WORK EXPERIENCE

**BIOSTRIVE** >> Software Engineer > Orlando, Florida

May 2024 - CURRENT

- Brainstormed and built a hosted website from the ground up with a team of developers while meeting all requirements of the webpage from higher ups
- Incorporated communication with all sectors of the company and worked towards finding tech needs for their problems

**WALMART** >> Food Team Associate > Warsaw , Indiana

October 2021 – CURRENT

- Enhanced customer experience to 50 customers daily with getting there needs met, while getting my job completed in a timely fashion
- Revamped a team of 4 people to a more efficient way of completing daily tasks that was noticed by higher ups
- Maintained cleanliness, order, promoted customer loyalty, satisfaction and purchases with consultative techniques and diligent attention to individual needs.

**WARSAW COMMUNITY SCHOOLS** >> *IT Specialist Intern* > Warsaw, IN

August 2021 - June 2022

- Accelerated the process of fixing up computer, ipads, and software issues for a school system of 2,500 kids while
  maintaining organization and communicating with my teammates
- Excelled in fixing various hardware issues, such as ipad screens, computer keyboards, non functional ram sticks, failed computer fans and returned all devices back to working order
- Upgraded old technology to their latest counterparts and replaced all needed components to work for the district without interruptions and keeping the teaching flow intact

### PROJECT EXPERIENCE

**Zike** >> Flask, React, Redux, PostgresQL, Sqlite, WTForms

Source Code > Live link

- Generated a dynamic way for users to add shoe sizes for a new shoe they want to create. With the created shoe they can add the size to their cart, favorite the shoe and checkout their items.
- Excelled by thoroughly planning the project and adhering strictly to the initial plans, I significantly reduced the occurrence of bugs, avoiding the distractions of spontaneous new ideas.

**WUBER EATS >>** Flask, React, Redux, PostgresQL, Sqlite, WTForms

**Source Code** > **Live Link** 

- Implemented fully functional shopping cart using react, redux and back end routes which created a modal where a user can see the items they added, add items and delete those items and update the quantity
- Excelled in communication with teammates on what to work on and how to merge our code together to compliment off each other instead of causing bugs

# **EDUCATION**

APP ACADEMY >> Full Stack Web Development

Completed June 2024

WARSAW COMMUNITY HIGH SCHOOL >> Technical and academic honors diploma >> Warsaw, IN

**Completed June 2022**